Finding Aid for Post Family Papers 1882-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Marjorie M. Post
  - Audio-recordings (tapes and phonorecords) of interviews with Marjorie M. Post and others
    - Interview of Hunter Marston, 1965 March, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-5-1]; mp3 file; (Judge Knott and Hunter Marston; on the subject of Palm Beach, Florida.)
    - Interview of Charles Mortimer, 1965 August, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3.75
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-6-1]; mp3 file; (On the subject of Topridge.)
    - Interview of Mr. Griffin, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-7-1]; mp3 file; (On the subject of construction and furnishings of Marjorie Merriweather Post's Florida home.)
    - Interview of Mr. Griffin, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-8-1]; mp3 file; (On the subject of construction and furnishings of Marjorie Merriweather Post's Florida home.)
    - Interview of Mr. Griffin, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-9-1]; mp3 file; (On the subject of construction and furnishings of Marjorie Merriweather Post's Florida home.)
    - Interview of Mr. Griffin, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-10-1]; mp3 file; (On the subject of construction and furnishings of Marjorie Merriweather Post's Florida home.)
    - Interview of Mr. Marston, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-11-1]; mp3 file; (Part 1; On the subject of E.F. Hutton.)
    - Interview of Mr. Marston, 1966 February 19, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-12-1]; mp3 file; (Part 2; On the subject of E.F. Hutton.)
    - Interview of Mr. Marston, 1966 February 19, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85519-SR-13-1]; mp3 file; (Part 3; On the subject of E.F. Hutton.)
    - Researcher use copies of interviews on reels in box 48 (Box 55)
  - Visual Materials
    The Post Family Visual Materials series consists of seven linear feet of photographs and six oversize photograph albums, primarily collected by Marjorie Merriweather Post. Many of the photographs and albums illustrate the various Post homes, notably her first Palm Beach residence called "Hogarcito," "Mar-a-Lago," and Hillwood. Mrs. Post was the owner of extensive collections of paintings, decorative arts and jewelry, many of which appear in the photographs of her homes, especially Hillwood in Washington, her New York apartment, and Mar-a-Lago in Palm Beach. Her collection of Indian materials was located at "Tregaron" summer home on Lake St. Regis in New York State. Camp Topridge is also represented by albums.
    Subjects covered by the photographs include the C.W. Post family, beginning with Charles Rollin Post, grandfather of the donor, the Postum Cereal Company, founded by C.W. Post, her life as wife of Ambassador Joseph Davies in Brussels, and various donations made to C.W. Post University in Long Island (located at Mrs. Post's former Roslyn, Long Island, home). There are also extensive albums and files on the Viscount airplane "Merriweather" and the Yacht "Hussah" (later called "Sea Cloud"). Painted and photographic portraits of Mrs. Post and her daughters, one of whom is the actress Dina Merrill, are included, and there are files and an album of Mrs. Post's wedding to her fourth husband, Herbert A. May, of Pittsburgh in 1958. Mrs. Post was a generous supporter of the Boy Scouts and the Red Cross, evidence of which also appears in the albums.
    - Photographs
      - Airplane, Viscount, "Merriweather." (Box 49)
      - Awards (Box 49)
      - C.W. Post University (Box 49)
      - Entertainment (Box 49)
      - Entertainment, Battle Creek High School Washington Tour (Box 49)
      - Entertainment, Veterans, Hillwood, 1970 (Box 49)
      - Family - Barzin, Eleanor Close (Box 49)
      - Family - Husbands, Daughters, Grandchildren (Box 49)
      - Family - Merrill, Dina (Box 49)
      - Family - Riggs, Adelaide Close (Box 49)
      - First Congregational Church, Fort Worth (Box 49)
      - Foreign Decorations (Box 49)
      - Jewelry and works of art (na 8959) (Box 49)
      - Kennedy Center Proposals (Box 49)
      - May, Herbert A. (Box 49)
      - May, Herbert A., Wedding to (see also albums) (Box 49)
      - Merriweather Family (Box 49)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
      - Mount Vernon Seminary (Box 49)
      - Post, Caroline Lathrop (Mrs. C.R. Post) (Box 49)
      - Post, Carroll R., Gardens, California 1938 (Box 49)
      - Post, Charles Rollin 1826-1919 (Box 49)
      - Post, Charles William
        - 1854-1914 (Box 49)
        - Post, Charles William, Dedication of statue, Lubbock, Texas (Box 49)
        - Monuments, Battle Creek (Box 49)
        - Portraits (Box 49)
        - Rainmaking, Texas and Battle Creek (see also albums) (Box 49)
      - Post, Ella Merriweather (Mrs. C.W. Post) (Box 49)
      - Post, Marjorie Merriweather
        - childhood to marriage (copy photos) (Box 49)
        - adulthood (Box 49)
        - 80th birthday, Washington, D.C. (Box 49)
        - Portraits - Bust (Box 49)
        - Portraits - Painted (Box 49)
        - Portraits - Painted, Chandor (Box 49)
        - Portraits, Photographic (Box 49)
      - Post City, Texas (Box 49)
      - Post Family (Crests heirlooms, graves, etc.) (Box 49)
      - Post Family, Coat of Arms (Box 49)
      - Postum Cereal Company
        - Personnel and Ads (Box 49)
        - Office Building and Art Collection (Box 49)
        - Officers (Box 49)
      - Red Cross Ball, Palm Beach 1967 (Box 49)
      - Residences
        - Old Hillwood (Roslyn, Long Island) - Boxwoods (Box 49)
        - Hillwood, Washington, D.C. (Box 49)
        - Hillwood, Washington, D.C. - Dedication of flagpole (Box 49)
        - Mar-a-Lago
          - Air Conditioning Work (Box 49)
          - Barwig Sculptures 1960s (Box 49)
          - Barwig Sculptures, (Jim Griffin photos) 1972 (Box 49)
          - Photos of E.F. Hutton Estate 1926 (Box 49)
            (copied from Columbia University, Butler Library, Joseph Urban collection)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
        - New York Apartment. Hotel Pierre 1973 (Box 49)
        - Rosewall, Pittsburgh (Box 49)
        - Topridge (Camp) (Box 49)
        - Tregaron (Box 49)
      - Yacht "Sea Cloud" (Box 49)
      - Yacht "Sea Cloud" - Duke and Duchess of Windsor, Guests (Box 49)
    - Photograph Albums
      - General
        - Farewell Garden Party in honor of the British Ambassador and Viscountess of Halifax, "Tregaron," Washington, D.C. May 6, 1946 (Box 50)
        - Interior design and plans, airplane "The Merriweather," Turboprop Viscount Jet, 4 Rolls Royce Engines. (Box 50)
        - Marjorie Merriweather Post's gift of painting of U.S. Constitution to U.S. Naval Academy (Box 50)
          [S.]
        - Yacht Hussar (1932/22 Trial Run Photos) - renamed Sea Cloud after divorce of Ed and Marjorie Hutton (Box 50)
      - Educational Institutions
        - Dedication and convocation, Merriweather Campus Long Island University, September 26, 1965 (Box 50)
        - Dedication Ceremonies, R. Gordon Hoxie Hall, Dr. Everett C. Jessup Health Center C.W. Post College, September 21, 1962 (Box 50)
        - Dedication Ceremonies, C.W. Post Athletic Field, Battle Creek, Michigan, November 3, 1961, 2 volumes (Box 51)
        - C.W. Post College- Sigma Alpha Epsilon (Mrs. Post made honorary housemother), 1969 (Box 51)
        - C.W. Post College- Sigma Alpha Epsilon (In State Latin Banquet ), November, 1969 (Box 51)
      - Family and Travel
        - Abroad,. Photo album abroad. 1904 (Box 51)
          "Coach and Four" trip through England by C.W. Post, Marjorie Post, Mrs. Carroll Post, Leila Young, Willis H. Post (cousin), wife and daughter Mary, 14 days
        - Family photos, snapshots, including first photos of Post City, Texas, circa 1907-1915 (Box 51)
        - Album of photos Charles Rollin Post (grandfather of Marjorie Merriweather Post) (Box 52)
        - Travel Snap shots, England, France, Germany,. Also Pasadena home of C.W. Leila; Indian Reservation, Yosemite, etc. 1903-1905 (Box 52)
        - Ella Merriweather Post Trip to Japan and China (Box 52)
        - Trip Abroad, [special location: B 302/10] 1904 (Volume 77)
          [special location: B 283/8]
          [77]
        - Cruise Around South America 1950 (Volume 72)
          [special location: B 283/6]
          [72]
      - Personal (Box 52)
        - Mrs. Post Presentations (Box 52)
        - Reception following marriage to Herbert May, at Rosewall (Pittsburgh) and Hillwood. 1958 (Box 52)
        - Marjorie Merriweather Post (to 1929) (Volume 75)
          [special location: B 283/8] [na 8417-na 8435]
          [75]
        - Boy Scouts, South Plains Council, Lubbock, Texas, 1961 (Box 53)
        - Hillwood flagpole presented to Marjorie Merriweather Post May on the occasion of her 75th birthday, March 15, 1962 (presentation ceremony October 20, 1962) (Box 53)
        - Ball in honor of Mrs. Joseph Edward Davies, American Legation, Luxembourg July 2, 1954 (Box 53)
        - American Embassy, Brussels 1938 (Box 53)
      - Residences
        - "Hogarcito," first Palm Beach Residence (sold in 1927), 2 volumes (Box 53)
        - Camp Topridge, Franklin County, New York, 2 volumes (Box 54)
        - Small album of Hillwood (Box 54)
        - Tregaron, McComb Street, Washington, D.C. 1942-1956 (Box 54)
        - Album, of house at 2 East 92nd Street, and of house on Foxhall Road 1915-1922, 1940-1942 (Box 54)
        - Marjorie and Joe Davies at Topridge (Box 54)
        - Album of Residences entitled "The Boulders, apartment of 375 Park Avenue and Auntie's House, Pasadena"x (Box 54)
          [removed]
        - Mar-a-Lago (Historic American Buildings Survey) 1968 (Box 54)
        - Mar-a-Lago, Palm Beach, Florida 1927 (Volume 73)
          [special location: B 283/6] [na 8412-na 8416]
          [73]
        - Hillwood, Rosilyn Long Island (Volume 74)
          [special location: B 283/7]
          [74]
        - "The Boulders" (Volume 76)
          [76]
      - Miscellaneous
        - Committee for a More Beautiful Capitol, circa 1965 (Box 55)
        - Life Magazine photos (Box 55)
        - Round and Square Dance 1954 (Box 55)
        - International Red Cross Gala, Palm Beach (Box 55)
    - Film
      - Garden Party, Washington, D.C., (also VHS copy) 1930s (Box 55)
      - (Hillwood introduction), 2 copies (Box 55)
        [Outsize]
  - Catalogues of Household furnishings and artwork
    The catalogues series consists of several sets of item listings of Post's art collections and household furnishings.
    - Household Catalogues 1-22 (Box 56)
    - Russian Collection Catalogues 1-28 (Box 56)
    - Catalogues of various small collection 29-45, 48, 62 (Box 57)
    - Agenda to Russian collection Catalogues 46-47 (+ 2 unnumbered) (Box 57)
    - Hillwood Agenda 53,56,60,63,64,68,71 (Box 57)
    - Camp Topridge Agenda 47, 52, 55, 58, 67, 78 (Box 57)
    - Items owned by Smithsonian Institution, 5 catalogues (Box 57)
  - Scrapbooks
    (The number in square brackets is an item number assigned by the Bentley Library)
    - Unnumbered sequence
      - 1898-circa 1913 (Volume 2)
        [2]
      - 1902-1903 (Volume 3)
        [3]
      - 1904-1905 (Volume 4)
        [4]
      - circa 1912-1915 (Volume 5)
        [5]
        (memory book)
      - 1913-1922 (Volume 6)
        [6]
      - 1912-1919 (Volume 7)
        [7]
      - 1914-1915 (Volume 8)
        [8]
      - 1919-1923 (Volume 9)
        [9]
      - 1926-1928 (Volume 10)
        [10]
      - 1926-1931 (Volume 11)
        [11]
      - 1932-1937 (Volume 12)
        [12]
      - 1937-1939 (Volume 13)
        [13]
      - circa 1908 (Volume 14)
        [14]
      - re stage actresses (Volume 15)
        [15]
      - 1964 (Volume 16)
        [16]
        (80th Birthday celebration)
      - 1968 (Volume 17)
        [17]
        (Camp Post, Boy Scout Camp, Lake Merriweather)
      - 1968 (Volume 18)
        [18]
      - 1968 (Volume 19)
        [19]
        (Red Cross Gala)
      - 1968 (Volume 20)
        [20]
        (Post City, Texas, historical marker dedication)
      - 1956 (Volume 21)
        [21]
        (Music for Young America)
      - 1958 (Volume 22)
        [22]
      - 1959 (Volume 23)
        [23]
    - Scrapbooks (numbered sequence)
      - Vol. 1 1940-1941 (Volume 24)
        [special location: B 285/5]
        [24]
      - Vol. 2 1941-1943 (Volume 25)
        [25]
      - Vol. 3 1943-1944 (Volume 26)
        [special location: B 285/6]
        [26]
      - Vol. 4 1944-1947 (Volume 27)
        [27]
      - Vol. 5 1948-1950 (Volume 28)
        [special location: B 285/7]
        [28]
      - Vol. 6 1950-1954 (Volume 29)
        [29]
      - Vol. 7 1954-1955 (Volume 30)
        [special location: B 285/8]
        [30]
      - Vol. 8 1956-1957 (Volume 31)
        [31]
      - Vol. 9] 1958-1959 (Volume 32)
        [special location: B 285/9
        [32]
      - Vol. 10 1960-1961 (Volume 33)
        [special location: B 285/9]
        [33]
      - Vol. 11 1962 (Volume 34)
        [special location: B 285/10]
        [34]
      - Vol. 12 1963 (Volume 35)
        [35]
      - Vol. 13 1964-1965 (Volume 36)
        [special location: B 285/11]
        [36]
      - Vol. 14 1965-1967 (Volume 37)
        [37]
      - Vol. 15 1967-1968 (Volume 38)
        [special location: B 285/12]
        [38]
      - Vol. 16 1969-1970 (Volume 39)
        [39]
      - Vol. 17 1973 (Volume 40)
        [special location: B 285/13]
        [40]
      - Vol. 18 1971-1972 (Volume 41)
        [41]